Micah Gilbert

(619)-272-1928 micahsgilbert@gmail.com

https://micahsgilbert.dev

Web Developer

■ SKILLS ■

I'm proficient in designing and implementing UIs in React.js, including when using frameworks like Material UI and Tailwind CSS. I'm also familiar with Jekyll for static site generation, Firebase and node.js for backends, GitHub Actions for CI, and have created personal projects using languages like Python, Java, and C.

In addition to my web skills, I've built up customer service experience in my work before college, and have gained significant experience using office software like the Google and Microsoft suites for various school-related tasks.

EXPERIENCE

UC San Diego Power Transformation Lab - San Diego, CA - Developer

February - November 2023

See my work at https://pwrlab.org

- Collaborated with Professor Michael Davidson and a graphic designer to revamp the lab's site, displaying the lab's research, team members, and opportunities in a modern, mobile friendly, and highly accessible layout.
 - Technologies used: Jekyll, HTML, Sass, JavaScript, GitHub Pages

TeachAids - Palo Alto, CA - Developer

April 2020 - September 2022

See my work at https://covidb.org and https://teachaids.org/for-concussions/crashcourse/

- Collaborated with large teams of college students and professionals from TeachAids, an organization dedicated to modernizing health education, to implement responsive UIs created by a graphic design team and implement automated web scraping and HTML parsing on the backend.
 - Technologies used: React.js, Material UI, Tailwind CSS, Python, GitHub Actions

Hy-Vee - Omaha, NE - Checker

June 2021 - August 2021

• Fulfilled checker and courtesy roles by providing customer service, fulfilling flexible time requirements, maintaining sales displays and shelves, efficiently operating a point-of-sale system, and performing and documenting cash drops.

EDUCATION

University of California, San Diego

September 2021 - Present

I'm majoring in Mathematics and minoring in Political Science at UCSD, with a 3.83 GPA